flydubai.com 2011-11-02

# Privacy policy - flydubai

This website is owned and managed by Dubai Aviation Corporation (trading as and hereinafter referred to as "flydubai").

We are responsible for the processing of any personal information you provide to this website and we are notified where required in each country under the relevant data protection legislation of that country.

We take our responsibilities regarding the protection of personal information very seriously. This policy explains:

  1. Why we need your personal information
  2. How we use your personal information
  3. To whom we disclose your personal information
  4. Access to/correction & updating of personal information
  5. Transfer of your personal information
  6. Consent
  7. Withdrawing your consent
  8. Security
  9. Tracking site usage
  10. Cookies
  11. Links
  12. Changes to the privacy policy
  13. Minors accessing our web site
  14. News and updates
  15. Applicable law

## 1\. Why we need your personal information

When you use services provided on this website, you will be asked to provide certain information such as your name, contact details and/or credit card details. We will store this information and hold it on computers or otherwise. We will use this information in the following ways:

  * to fulfill our agreement with you, including processing your flight, sending you your itinerary or contacting you if there is a problem with your booking;

  * to register you with our website and administer our website services where you have registered to receive these. You can unsubscribe from these services at any time (see choice/opt-out below);

  * to administer any contest or other promotional offer you may enter and notify winners;

  * to answer any queries which you may send to us by e-mail;

  * in order to conduct customer satisfaction surveys;

  * to meet our legal compliance obligations;

  * for crime prevention and detection; and

  * for direct marketing purposes, as set out in detail below.

We need to know the names of all passengers travelling. If you are booking a flight on behalf of someone else, you must obtain their consent to use their personal information. We proceed on the basis that you have obtained this consent.

We may require the name and contact details of a third party whom we may contact in an emergency. It is your responsibility to ensure that the third party consents to the disclosure of the information provided for that purpose.

Back to top

## 2\. How we use your personal information

Information you provide or that is obtained by us on this website, via our call centre or a travel agent will be used by us to provide you and other customers (via mail, e-mail, telephone or otherwise) with information about new products and services and special offers we think you will find valuable. We may also inform you about new products and services and special offers of selected third parties, where you have registered to receive these.

We may contact you by post, e-mail, telephone (including SMS) or fax for these purposes. Your confirmation e-mails (which may include details of flight bookings or other services booked through our website) may include marketing material which we may feel will be of interest to you from other third parties. We may also use and analyse the information that we collect so that we can review, administer, support, improve and develop our business and the services which we offer.

If you would like to receive details of our new services and special offers, you can sign up here.

Back to top

## 3\. To whom we disclose your personal information

flydubai does not sell or trade your personal information to third parties. We may share information about you as follows:

  * Your personal data (including sensitive personal data) has been provided to us for the purposes of: making a reservation; recording and issuing a booking; issuing a boarding pass and other purposes associated with or incidental to your carriage. You authorise us to retain and use such data and to transmit to and/or to share it with: our own offices, our authorised agents, our other companies and/or brands, anyone to whom we transfer our rights and duties; third party companies offering related services (including, for example, car rental, hotels, limousines, transfers andancillary services), governments and government agencies, credit card and other payment card companies, and other airlines or providers of such related services.

  * For all these purposes, flydubai may provide its third party service providers and processors with access to your personal information. These service providers may include: credit card verification providers, our data warehouse and customer relationship management centre, marketing organisations, who may provide us support with marketing and promotional communications; internet service providers who administer our web pages and provide internet services and host our facilities; third party companies offering related services, such as chauffeurs, car rental agencies, hotels and other ancillary services; and consumer research companies that assist flydubai with understanding consumer interests by conducting surveys.

  * flydubai may also disclose your personal information as permitted or required by law. For example, flydubai will disclose personal information to those governmental bodies who have authority to obtain it, in order to comply with a warrant or subpoena issued by a court of competent jurisdiction, and to comply with record production requirements.

  * To customs and/or immigration departments or other regulatory authorities in your country of departure and/or destination in order to comply with the law in those countries.

  * Sensitive personal data, for example, data relating to your health or disabilities, religion, criminal record or otherwise may be processed by us. You recognise that, by providing us with sensitive personal data, you give your explicit consent for us to process it and disclose it to third parties for the above purposes. We undertake to collect, process, store, save and transfer your data in compliance with relevant data protection legislation in force from time to time. In processing your data, we may transfer it to countries which may not afford the same level of protection.

  * To anyone to whom we transfer or may transfer our rights and duties under our agreement with you.

  * If we have a duty to do so or if the law allows us to do so.

  * To our employees and agents to do any of the above on our behalf, now or in the future.

If you choose not to provide certain personal information we request, you will still be able to visit our website, but you may be unable to access certain options or services.

Please note that there may be instances where it may be necessary for us to communicate with you, for administrative or operational reasons relating, for example, to advise you of alterations to flights.

The information that you provide to us will be held in our systems, which are located on our premises or those of an appointed third party. We may also allow access to your information by other third parties who act for us for the purposes set out in this policy or for other purposes approved by you.

flydubai only shares your personal information to the extent required for the performance of such services. flydubai has implemented safeguards to ensure that our service providers treat personal information in a way that is consistent with the terms of this privacy policy and that it is never used except to fulfil services to flydubai.

Back to top

## 4\. Access to/correction & updating of personal information

You have the right to see personal information we keep about you. We will endeavour to provide the information you require within a reasonable time. There may be a small monetary charge for some requests, depending on the information requested.

If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, we provide a way to correct, update or remove your personal information provided to us.

Back to top

## 5\. Transfer of your personal information

Some parties that process or store personal information may be located in jurisdictions outside your country of residence. Therefore, your information may be processed and stored in these jurisdictions and, as a result, foreign governments, courts, or law enforcement or regulatory agencies may be able to obtain disclosure of your information through the laws in these countries.

Back to top

## 6\. Consent

By choosing to provide flydubai with your personal information, you are consenting to its use in accordance with the principles outlined in this privacy policy and as outlined at the time you are asked to provide any personal information. flydubai may contact you by phone or e-mail in order to provide you with updates pertaining to its services as well as information about additional offers, products or events that flydubai believes may be of interest to you. You can choose to unsubscribe to these updates or from having your personal information used for market research purposes.

If you have any further questions about our privacy policy or its implementation, you can contact us here. If there are changes to this privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and in what circumstances we disclose it.

Back to top

## 7\. Withdrawing your consent

Marketing communications sent to you by flydubai will provide you with options to withdraw your consent. If you no longer wish to receive promotional materials, you may opt-out of receiving these communications. You will always be notified when information is being collected by any outside parties.

Please note that if you do not consent to flydubai's use and disclosure of your personal information, this may affect our ability to provide you with particular products and services.

Back to top

## 8\. Security

We take appropriate steps to protect the personal information you share with us. When you book a flight or enter personally identifying information, your details are transmitted across the internet securely using high-grade encryption (128 bit). We have implemented technology and security features to safeguard the privacy of your personal information. We also follow strict security procedures in the storage and disclosure of information which you have given us to prevent unauthorised access. Should we be required to disclose sensitive information to you, we may request proof of identity in adherence with our security procedures before we are able to do so.

In the circumstances set out in this policy where flydubai passes your information to a third party, we will ensure that the security measures that such party has in place in relation to the processing of your data are at least as stringent as those employed by flydubai. This does not apply where we are required by law to pass your information to a third party.

We will retain your information for a reasonable period or as long as the law requires.

You can book and pay in all confidentiality and security, provided that the terms and regulations of use are strictly respected.

Back to top

## 9\. Tracking site usage

We use tracking software to monitor customer traffic patterns and site usage and to gather certain information like the number and frequency of visitors to the site. This information (which may include the URL you just came from, the URL you next go to, what browser you are using and your IP address) is used to develop the design and layout of the site to better meet the needs of visitors to www.flydubai.com. We only use such data in the aggregate. This software does not capture any personally identifying information.

This information is also used to analyse patterns and improve our marketing and promotional efforts, to improve our content and product offerings, and to customise our site's content, layout and services.

Back to top

## 10\. Cookies

A 'cookie' is a small bit of text used by a browser to store information. When you visit a site that uses cookies, the web server will request permission to pass a cookie to your browser. If accepted, it will occupy only a few bytes on your hard drive and can improve your web surfing experience.

flydubai uses cookies to track customer visits through its site. Cookies cannot profile your system or collect information from your hard drive. And although you may receive cookies from many different sites, each cookie can only be read by the web server that originally issued it. Please note that this information is for our use only. We do not disclose or share this information with any third parties.

Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but if you do not wish this to happen, you can change the cookie settings in your browser to prevent this. Even without a cookie, you can use most of the features on the web site. Our cookies do not contain any personally identifying information.

Cookies may also be used in e-mail messages that you have agreed to receive and onour website to help us measure the effectiveness of our advertising and how visitors use our site.

Back to top

## 11\. Links

Our website may contain links to other websites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of websites not operated by flydubai. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy policy applies solely to information collected by our website.

Back to top

## 12\. Changes to the privacy policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post thechanges on our website so you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. This privacy policy may be amended by flydubai from time to time. Use of the website after the effective date of the amendments constitutes acceptance of the amended terms and conditions. We reserve the right to apply the amended terms to the information we have already collected, subject to any legal constraints.

If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify you by way of an e-mail. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in this manner.

Back to top

## 13\. Minors accessing our web site

flydubai cannot distinguish the age of peopleaccessing its website. If a minor (according to applicable laws) has provided flydubai with information without consent of a parentor guardian, the parent or guardian can contact flydubai to remove it.

Back to top

## 14\. News and updates

We will occasionally inform you about our special offers and new services via your e-mail address. You only receive our e-mails regarding news and special offers once you subscribe to this service. If you do not wish to receive these e-mails, you can unsubscribe at any time. Once you have unsubscribed, your e-mail address will be removed from the distribution list.

Back to top

## 15\. Applicable law

In case of dispute relating to the enforcement and/or construction of the present terms, flydubai will do its best to reach an amicable settlement, and in case of failure, the dispute will be submitted to the jurisdiction of the UAE courts. The applicable law is UAE law.

Back to top  
  
---  
Your name |    
   
Recipient's name |    
   
Recipient's e-mail |    
   
|    
  
|  Send E-mail
